Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpurohit, I am MBA Finance of Founder Family First Financial
Services, I have been working in the corporate sector for 14 years and
today I am presenting to you that in March 2025, SBI Life Insurance
launched a child plan keeping children in mind, which is named Smart
Future Star. Before this, in March 2025 itself, they
had launched a new product called Young Achiever, which was a guaranteed plan and this Future Star plan
is a participating policy which will participate in the profit of the company and
you will get maturity in this bonus based policy. You will get both these plans
with almost the same features, a little difference is that the Young Achiever plan
is a 100% guaranteed plan, once you buy the policy, there will never
be a difference in the rate maturity, whereas the maturity you will get in Future Star
will depend on the bonus declared by the company every year, so watch this video completely, if you like the video,
then definitely subscribe to
my YouTube channel Anil Rajpurohit FFFS. You will find over 300 insurance-related videos.
Even SBI's new plan, Young Achiever,
will be available on this channel, which will help you in financial planning. Regarding the eligibility criteria of this policy,
there will be two options, proposer and life to be insured.
The age of the proposer can be from 18 to 55 years. And
you can take the policy for the life insured, who will be children, son or daughter, whose minimum age
should be between 30 days to 15 years. The minimum age at maturity will be 18 years and
the maximum age at maturity will be 35 years. Here,
you have the option of premium payment of 7 years, 10 years and 12 years. There was no option of 12 years in Young Achhe,
but in Future Star, the option of premium payment of 12 years is also given.
You can keep any policy term between 15 to 25. 15, 16, 17, 18, 20 22
25 You can select any policy term here The minimum premium here
will be ₹0000 The minimum sum assured will be ₹ lakh Here you
can pay the premium in yearly mode You can pay in monthly mode You can
pay in quarterly mode Option of quarterly mode
is not given in this policy Talking about maturity in this policy, here the maturity will be sum maturity
plus revisionary bonus plus terminal bonus If the company declares,
then all three will be given together Sum Maturity means
death benefit in a sum policy, so here in death benefit you will get sum or death plus revisionary bonus
plus terminal bonus if any, if the company has declared it or 105 per cent of the total premium paid,
whichever is higher among the two, you will get as age benefit Sum Assured
means sum assured or 11 times the annual premium The biggest feature of this plan
is that it has inbuilt waiver Rider waiver of premium The benefit of waiver of premium
is inbuilt in this policy. For this, you do not have to pay any additional premium.
In case of the death of the proposer or his accidental total and permanent disability,
the premium payment is waived. Let us assume that the father
has purchased the policy for his son and unfortunately he dies, then
all the remaining premiums will be waived. The child will definitely get the maturity amount. If
the father does not die but he becomes disabled in an accident, he becomes totally permanently
disabled. You can see all its definitions on the side.
In that case also, if the father is alive but disabled, even then the premium payment will be waived and
the child will definitely get the maturity amount.
The option of settlement of the amount that is going to come to you has been given where you will get three options.
The first option is that you can defer the maturity amount from one year to seven years.
Suppose you have decided that you want to defer the maturity amount. The maturity is going to come in the 20th year, if you
want to take it after a year i.e. in the 21st year or after two years i.e.
in the 22nd year or after seven years i.e. in the 27th year, you can take it and
you will also get interest on it. The second option given to you is that you can take this maturity which
is going to come instead of taking it as a long sum but you can take it in monthly mode or quarterly mode
or yearly mode between 2 years to 7 years, that is, if you have decided
that you want to take this total maturity every year for 7 years, you
can take it. The third option given to you is that you can take some money as a lump sum or
take it in one go and the rest you can take as income every year or as monthly income also.
If you want to take it, you can take it. You will also get a discount in this policy.
You will get discount on the sum asset. Suppose your insurance cover sum assured is more than 10 lakhs.
Let's say your sum assured is 15 lakhs and the policy term is for 25 years, then you
will get a discount of up to 45%. If you are a staff of SBI Life Insurance or any
other type of branch of SBI, if you are a staff of SBI, then you will get a discount of up to 7%.
Now let's understand this plan
with benefit illustration. SBI Life Insurance
Benefit Illustration SB La Smart Future Star Plan
is an individual plan. Non-linked means it is not linked to the share market. Participating means
it will participate in the bonus and is a saving product. Here there is a customer whose age is 35 years
and he has a new born baby whose age is just one month and he
purchases the policy for him where he is selecting a policy term of 20 years.
He will pay the premium for 10 years and his premium without GST will be around ₹ lakh.
There will be an insurance cover of 13 lakhs and your bonus will be calculated on 13 lakhs only. This insurance
cover will be for the child. If the proposer dies or becomes disabled,
the premiums are waived. For the first year, GST will be 45%. Then for the remaining years, GST
will be 2%. So, in the first year, the premium will be 10,4297 with GST and
for the remaining years, the premium will be 051%. Here you will see in the second column
where you have to pay the premium for 10 years. After that, you
do not have to pay the premium. And here you will see two-three columns. Guaranteed benefit. Non-
guaranteed benefit as per 4%. Non-guaranteed benefit as per %. So, as per
the IID norms, this cannot be shown more than 8%. So, this table has been created accordingly.
You can see the maturity benefit in column number 17 where it is 8% including
terminal bonus, revisional bonus, which will be revisional bonus, terminal bonus and
sum which will be calculated in the beginning. It was 13 lakhs, by combining these three you will get maturity
, how much will be the maturity amount? 27 lakhs 1750,
you will get maturity amount. You will get 27 lakhs 1750 lakhs for 10 years, 27000 for 20 years
, if you get bonus of 4%, then you will get 14,64000, whereas what was in Young Achiever Plan,
not four or eight, there was no problem, there is a match of around 24 lakhs, but
that is a 100% guarantee, there is not even a rupee less or more in it, but here
if the company provides bonus up to 27 lakhs in this manner, then you can get this maturity,
by the way, SBI Life Insurance is a 25-year-old company and
declares bonus every year, so you will definitely get bonus, how much
you will get depends on the profit of the company every year, which can be less or more,
but you will definitely get bonus, here you will see that revisionary bonus
is written in column number 12, total, here you will see this total amount also You can see that
you have got revisionary bonus of 111000 rupees, plus you had a sum of 13 lakhs, plus
including terminal etc., your total maturity comes to 27 lakhs. In this way, you
can see this calculation. Let us understand it with another example, suppose there
is a customer and he is purchasing the same policy, but this time he is
taking a policy term of 25 years as premium, taking a premium payment term of 12 years, and
pays 228000 without GST and premium, so here this time
you will see his maturity, the maturity will be of ₹ crore, the tax free maturity is of ₹ crore,
you have to pay only 2 lakhs for something like 12 years, after 25 years, you
can take maturity up to one crore, plus here, this death benefit will be there for the child, I will explain
that for example,
one premium was paid in the policy and the father dies, then what will happen in this case,
The remaining 228000 which were 11 premiums will be waived off, that means SBI Life
Insurance will pay it itself and the maturity amount of Rs. 1 crore for the child
based on bonus will come to him on maturity.
Now let us understand with another example that suppose after 5 years the child dies,
the father is alive but the child dies, then what is the death benefit in the fifth year,
around 50 lakhs, then 50 lakhs will be given to the family, the policy will be closed, if the child
dies untimely then the policy will be closed, if the father dies or becomes disabled
then the premiums will be waived, the policy will continue and maturity will be available,
so you can see this policy in this way, this
benefit of waiver of premium is inbuilt, in other companies you
have to purchase it by paying additional premium, whereas in this policy it is inbuilt, you do not have to pay any separate premium.
Here, if you want to take a loan up to 50% of the surrender value, you can take the loan and
the maturity comes tax free in the income tax rate 10 10D.
Talking about the other benefits and features of this policy, first of all, let us see
the benefit of surrender benefit and RPU. In this policy, you
will get special surrender value generated after one premium is paid. Guaranteed surrender value
will be generated after paying two full premiums. If due to some reason you are unable to pay the premium,
you can also get this policy reduced paid up or you can also get RPU done, where
you get the benefit in the proportion in which you have paid the premium.
In this policy, you will also get a loan up to 50% of the surrender value.
You get tax benefits in the income tax section ATC, which may be stopped in future due to the income tax or new
slabs etc. coming, but the most important one is 10 10D,
where maturity comes tax free, so this feature is the most important. It is important that suppose you
are paying a premium of ₹ lakh and beyond that you
are getting a maturity of more than one crore, then the entire maturity is tax free for you, in the rest,
tax free maturity is not available as of today's date, plus now you must be seeing that the share
market is also going down a lot, many people must be thinking that
we can also plan child education and marriage through SIP, you can do that too, but
what is the biggest feature of this plan, let's assume that you did a SIP of ₹ 00 and
purchased this policy of ₹ 00, suppose tomorrow your father dies, then who will pay for the second SIP,
no one will pay, but here the premiums will be waived and the maturity that was to come,
25-30 lakhs, whatever it was, it will definitely come, so in this way it is
giving the benefit of an insurance cover, giving tax benefits as well, you are also getting returns, there
is also no fear of the share market that it will be less or more, once you have taken the policy,
the rates will be fixed Plus options for premium burning measure are also given
in case of disability and in case of death. If we talk about free look period and grace period,
then you will get both these periods of 30 days and revival period will be of 5 years.
If for any reason you are not able to pay the premium on time, even after one or two years,
you can revive the policy by paying late fees etc.
If you want to purchase this plan by comparing and consulting that which other company has similar plan
available where you will get more maturity or less maturity,
in which plan you can get more maturity, if you can
consult and compare, then you can call
me on the below given number 9094 0 3412.